inov-8.com 2019-07-26

# Privacy & Cookie Policy | inov-8

## Privacy Policy

We, inov-8 (Inoveight Limited) are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy. We use the information you share with us to make our services and your experience continually better. This policy (together with our Terms & Conditions and any other document referred to in it) sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us. By visiting inov-8.com (“our site”) you are accepting and consenting to the practices described in this policy. For the purpose of the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) 2018 (the “Act”), the data controller is: Inoveight Limited, 12B Beechburn, Prospect Road, Crook, County Durham, DL15 8RA, England.

### INFORMATION WE MAY COLLECT FROM YOU

We may collect and process the following data about you: Information you give us. You may give us information about you by filling in forms on our site or on our social media pages or profiles, or by corresponding with us by phone, e-mail or otherwise. It includes information you provide when you register to use our site and may include your name, address, e-mail address and phone number. Information we collect about you. With regard to each of your visits to our site we may automatically collect the following information: technical information, e.g. about your browser or the device you use to access the site and the Internet Protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the internet.; information about your visit, e.g. which website you clicked through to reach ours, lengths of visits to pages , products you viewed or searched for, page interaction information (such as scrolling, clicks, and mouse-overs).

### USES MADE OF THE INFORMATION

We use information held about you in the following ways: Information you give to us. We will use this information to carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us and to provide you with the information, products and services that you request from us; to provide you with information about other goods and services we offer that are similar to those that you have already purchased or enquired about; to provide you, with information about goods or services we feel may interest you. If you are an existing customer, we may contact you by electronic means (e-mail or SMS) with information about goods and services similar to those which were the subject of a previous sale or negotiations of a sale to you. Information we collect about you. We will use this information: to administer, operate and improve our site and ensure it is presented in the most effective manner; as part of our efforts to keep our site safe and secure; to make suggestions and recommendations to you and other users of our site about goods or services that may interest you or them. Information we receive from other sources. We may combine this information with information you give to us and information we collect about you and use it for the purposes set out above.

### DISCLOSURE OF YOUR INFORMATION

We may share your personal information with any member of our group, including our US subsidiary inov-8 inc. and you should only give us your information if you consent to this. If inov-8 inc. or substantially all of its assets are acquired by a third party, in which case personal data held by it about its customers will be one of the transferred assets. If we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal, or in order to enforce or apply our Terms & Conditions. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for the purposes of fraud protection. 

### WHERE WE STORE YOUR PERSONAL DATA

The data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the Economic Area (“EEA”). It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA work for us or for one of our suppliers. Such staff maybe engaged in, among other things, the fulfilment of your order, the processing of your payment details and the provision of support services. By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We will take all reasonably necessary steps to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy. All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers. Any payment transactions will be encrypted using SSL technology. Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our site, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share a password with anyone. Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our site; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.

All personal marketing data that we store on our customers is stored, protected and processed in Mailchimp. Any data collected at events will be shatred with our partners. Please view their [Privacy Policy](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/) and [Terms](https://mailchimp.com/legal/terms/)

Also, if you enter a competition with us, we store your information in our wishpond database. Please review their [Privacy Policy](https://www.wishpond.com/privacy-policy/) and [Terms](https://www.wishpond.com/terms-conditions/)

Please be aware that if you request to have your data removed from our database, it will be removed from both the above databases.

### YOUR RIGHTS

You have the right to ask us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes. You can also exercise the right at any time by emailing Enquiries though our contact us form. Our site may, from time to time, contain links to and from third party websites. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that those websites should have their own privacy policies and we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites.

### PRODUCT REVIEWS & CUSTOMER SERVICE REVIEW PLATFORM

We reserve the right to send a number of transactional emails once an order has been placed online. We will send an order confirmation, status updates and dispatch emails. Our logisitcs partner will also send a combination of SMS/email correspondence to advise on status of your delivery.

Fourteen days after an order has been pleaced we will send an email no-reply@inov-8.com, asking the customer for product review feedback on the product(s) you have purchased. When a review has been left it will be set to pending upon review. If you wish to be unsubscribed from any future email please click the link in the footer of the email. 

Seven days after an order has been pleaced we will send an email from Trustpilot, asking them to for feedback on the service you have been given. When a review has been left it will automatically be visible unless there has been inflammotry content added. If you wish to be unsubscribed from any future email please click the link in the footer of the email. This will remove the email address from Trustpilot's review system they will receive no further emails from them, regardless of where they shop. Further emails will be sent out if the first email is not acknowledged.

### ACCESS TO INFORMATION AND WITHDRAWING CONSENT

The Act gives you the right to access information held about you. You may request from us a copy of personal data we hold on you.

You may at any time withdraw your consent with future effect and without affecting the lawfulness of processing of your Personal Data based on the consent you provided before you withdrew it, and exercise other controls regarding website and online data collection, interest-based advertising, your communication settings, and app preferences. Depending on the Service, collection and use of Personal Data may be required for the Services to work.

### DATA RETENTION

We will retain your Personal Data for as long as you maintain an account or as otherwise necessary to provide you the Services. We will also retain your Personal Data as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

Where we no longer need to process your Personal Data for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy, we will delete your Personal Data from our systems.

Where permissible, we will also delete your Personal Data upon your request. If you would like us to delete your data, please email Enquiries though our Contact Us form with your name and e-mail address and also provide exact instructions to “Delete your personal data and/or any data we store relating to you”

If you have questions about our data retention practices, please contact us through our main website e-mail enquiries from our Contact Us page.

### SECURITY

We implement appropriate technical and organizational safeguards to protect against unauthorized or unlawful processing of Personal Data and against accidental or unlawful destruction, loss, alteration, unauthorized disclosure of, or access to Personal Data. Please be advised, however, that we cannot fully eliminate security risks associated with the storage and transmission of Personal Data.

 **Links to Other Websites.** Please note that this Privacy Policy does not apply to the practices of companies that we do not own or control or to people that we do not employ or manage. Our Services may provide a link or otherwise provide access to Third Party Sites. We provide these links merely for your convenience. We have no control over, do not review, and are not responsible for Third Party Sites, their content, or any goods or services available through the Third Party Sites. Our Privacy Policy does not apply to Third Party Sites, and any data you provide to Third Party Sites, you provide at your own risk. We encourage you to review the privacy policies of any Third Party Sites with that you interact with.

### CHILDREN

We do not knowingly collect Personal Data online from children under 13 (note that the minimum age may vary based on country/region, and on local law). If you become aware that a child has provided us with Personal Data without parental consent, please e-mail Enquiries through our Contact Us Page. If we become aware that a child under 13 has provided us with Personal Data without parental consent, we will take steps to remove the data and cancel the child's account.

### CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY

Any changes we may make to our privacy policy in the future will be posted on this page and, where appropriate, notified to you by e-mail. Please check back frequently to see any updates or changes to our privacy policy.

### CONTACT

We welcome questions, comments and requests regarding this privacy policy. They should addressed to: Inoveight Limited, 12B Beechburn, Prospect Road, Crook, County Durham, DL15 8RA, England or to email Enquiries though our Contact Us form.

## **COOKIES**

### WHAT ARE COOKIES AND HOW ARE THEY USED?

Cookies are small text files that are stored on your computer when you visit some websites, which help to provide you with a more tailored experience whenever you visit the website. We use cookies on inov-8.com to make the website easier for you to use, and to help inform us on how to improve the website to make it easier for you to shop online and navigate our features. We do not store any personally identifiable information about you in our cookies, and cookies cannot be used to harm your computer.

### COOKIES SET BY inov-8.com

A list of cookies used on the inov-8.com website is shown below, along with a brief description explaining what we use these for.

COOKIES SET BY inov-8.com Cookie| Purpose  
---|---  
Session cookie | These cookies are used to store your shopping activity throughout your individual session on the site, enabling us to maintain your basket across the site and checkout.  
Locale selection | These cookies are used to store information about your preferred shipping location, to ensure that we display the correct pricing and delivery options for all products on the website.   
Remember Me | Keeps your inov-8 account logged in on your computer when you have selected the option to “Remember Me” when you log into your account.   
Persistent Basket | We use this cookie to store an encrypted key which we can use to reinstate your basket for up to 30 days.  
  
### inov-8 also works with a selection of third parties to help us improve our website experience.

### COOKIES SET BY THIRD PARTY SERVICES

COOKIES SET BY THIRD PARTY SERVICES Cookie| Purpose  
---|---  
Google Analytics Coremetrics Analytics | Used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited.  
Doubleclick | These cookies and tags are used to collect non-personal information about how visitors interact with advertising served on other websites before they arrive at inov-8 and which advertisements our customers prefer. This information helps inov-8 deliver ads that are relevant to your interests, control the number of times you see a given ad, and measure the effectiveness of advertising campaigns. You can opt out of this service at [http://www.youradchoices.com](http://www.youradchoices.com/)  
Twitter | If you click a ‘Tweet’ link on the inov-8 website, Twitter sets a cookie to remember that you have ‘tweeted’ that information.  
Google+ | If you click a ‘+1’ link on the inov-8  website, Google sets a cookie to remember that you have ‘+1’ that information.  
Facebook | If you click a ‘Like’link on the inov-8  website, facebook sets a cookie to remember that you have ‘Liked’ that information.  
Cloud IQ | These are targeting cookies that record your visit to our website so we can send basket reminders should you wish to receive them.  
  
### 

HOW DO I MANAGE COOKIES SET BY inov-8?

If you wish to restrict, delete or block web browser cookies which are set on your device then you can do this through your browser settings; the Help function within your browser should tell you how.
